Guide to the Candida Scott Piel Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Printed Materials, 1950-2003; Series III
  - Time [vol. 154, nos. 9, 12], 1999 August 30, September 20 (Box 19)
  - Tulip [no. 3], undated (Box 19)
  - Turf, 1998 (Box 19)
  - The 12th Annual Awards Ceremony & Thank You Party, 1995 November 5 (Box 19)
  - "Uniforms: Reference and Sources", undated (Box 19)
  - We Celebrate Freedom [souvenir program], undated (Box 19)
  - "The White Party 10thAnniversary", undated (Box 19)
  - "With the Greatest of Ease" [program], undated (Box 19)
  - Womanbooks lesbian booklist [2 issues], undated (Box 19)
  - Womanbooks "Reading, Writing, and Rhythm" [vol. 1, nos. 1, 3-4], undated (Box 19)
  - "Womanbooks Review" [vol. 3, no. 5], undated (Box 19)
  - Women's Magazine, 2000 July (Box 19)
  - Yale Alumni Magazine [vol. 61, no. 7], 1998 May (Box 19)
  - "Yale GALA" [newsletter; vol. 11, no. 1], 1994 September (Box 19)
- Memorabilia, 1979-2003; Series IV
  The series is arranged alphabetically by type of material, with a box of miscellaneous items at the end. The substantial number of t-shirts, hats, pins, and matchbooks from various gay events are particularly good documentation of the material history of gay culture in the 1980s and 1990s.
  - Cloth, 1984, undated (Box 20)
  - Combs, undated (Box 20)
  - Cups [plastic], 1984-1985, undated (Box 20)
  - Cushion: Gay Games IV, 1994 June 18 (Box 21)
  - Flag: Stonewall 25, 1994 (Box 21)
  - Hats, 1987, 1994, 1998, undated (Box 22)
  - Matchbooks, 1987-1997, undated (Box 23)
  - Passes, badges, etc., Circa 1986-2003, undated (Box 24)
  - Pins, Circa 1979-1999, undated (Box 25–26)
  - Plaster: "'Dennis' by M. Brooks Jones ('86 NYC Theme Button SF Bulldog Baths)", 1986 (Box 27)
  - Safe sex kits, 1990, undated (Box 28)
  - Stockings, undated (Box 29)
  - T-shirts and other clothing
    - Morgan Stanley-Diversity (Box 30)
    - GMCH Softball Benefit 1990 (Box 30)
    - Pride Rally 6/23/96-Backstage (Box 30)
    - NYC Gay and Lesbian Pride 6/21/98 Backstage (Box 30)
    - Stonewall 25 6/26/94 March to the UN (Box 30)
    - NYC Dance 6/28/92 Security (Box 30)
    - NYC Lesbian and Gay Pride Dance 6/29/97 Talent (Box 30)
    - Razor Sharp, Be Fabulous (Box 30)
    - PRIDE [tank top] (Box 30)
    - Lesbian and Gay Pride, Boston 1997 (Box 30)
    - NYC Pride 6/21/98-The Rally (Box 30)
    - Cleveland Pride Family Reunion 1997 (Box 30)
    - Hotlanta River Expo 1991 (Box 30)
    - Toronto Pride '99 (Box 30)
    - Male genitalia design by Tricycle 75 (Box 30)
    - Stonewall 20 6/25/89-STAFF (Box 30)
    - Dignity 7th Biennial Convention-NYC 1985 (Box 30)
    - Missed Liberty 6/30/86 U.S. Supreme Court/Bower v. Hardwick (Box 30)
    - San Francisco Lesbian and Gay Freedom Day 6/24/84-MEDIC (Box 30)
    - Tribe 2002 [AmFAR AIDS Research] (Box 30)
    - The March 6/28/92 NYC-MARSHALL (Box 31)
    - The Names Project National Tour 88 (Box 31)
    - The Rally, 6/18/95-BACKSTAGE (Box 31)
    - Pride Day 6/28/97 NYC-MARSHALL THE MARCH THE RALLY (Box 31)
    - Cherry Grove Beach Hotel-Ice Palace-STAFF (Box 31)
    - GMHC 8th Annual Morning Party 1990 (Box 31)
    - Stonewall 20, SF 6/25/89-SAFETY MONITOR (Box 31)
    - Raise the Rainbow 6/26/94 NYC (Box 31)
    - Festival de Cannes 1993-Cinema against AIDS [AmFAR benefit] (Box 31)
    - Leather Pride Night NYC (Box 31)
    - Stonewall 25 6/25-6/26/94 NYC (Box 31)
    - Keith Haring pride logo [2 t-shirts] (Box 31)
    - First run Keith Haring design for Heritage and Pride 1986 (Box 31)
    - Wild Side [Long Island based gay magazine, 1980s] (Box 31)
    - Take a Ferry on the Fourth-Our 10th Annual Celebration 7/4/87 (Box 31)
    - Second Gay American Arts Festival NYC 6/81 (Box 32)
    - 3-Dollar Bill Theater [Post, Glines and Meridian Gay Theater Co.] (Box 32)
    - The Spike NYC (Box 32)
    - NYC 1980 First Gay American Arts Festival (Box 32)
    - Interpride 98 (Box 32)
    - F. I. Pines Fashion Show Benefit (Box 32)
    - Stonewall 20 [New York City Heritage of Pride t-shirt] (Box 32)
    - Stonewall 25 [New York City Heritage of Pride 94] (Box 32)
    - Fire Island bus service and New York City social events (Box 32)
    - Phoenix Rising-Benefit for Body Positive 11/26/95 (Box 32)
    - TDK + TMB 85 [New York disco kazoo and tambourine marching band] (Box 32)
    - Great Peace March 1986 [New York disco kazoo and tambourine participation] (Box 32)
    - NJ Pride '93-STAFF (Box 32)
    - New York City gay pride rally Union Square Park (Box 32)
    - Heritage of Pride Rally 6/21/98 Bryant Park (Box 32)
    - Unity and More in 84, SF L/G Freedom Day 6/24/84 (Box 32)
    - Alive with pride in 85, South Florida (Box 32)
    - Castro shirt (Box 32)
    - Mary's Naturally [gay bar shorts] (Box 32)
    - Unity and More in '84 Remember Stonewall 15th Anniversary (Box 33)
    - Leatherfest IV San Diego (Box 33)
    - This is your Brain. This is your Brain on Pride. Any Questions? [1991 Heritage of Pride, Inc.] (Box 33)
    - Mister Drummer (Box 33)
    - NYSLGL: Making Our Rights a Reality (Box 33)
    - OZ. Cherry Jubilee II WDC 97 (Box 33)
    - Wicked. The After Hours Party for Naughty Children Who Will Not Go to Sleep (Box 33)
    - Our City-Our Future METROPOLIS (Box 33)
    - T-shirt with drawing [Alchemy II] (Box 33)
    - Climax [AmFAR AIDS Research] (Box 33)
    - Erie party Cleveland '98 (Box 33)
    - The INVASION of the GROVE II. FAIRPAC PINES INVADER (Box 33)
    - VOLUNTEER [Pines 2001] (Box 33)
    - Big Guns Dance On Manhattan June 26, 1994 (Box 33)
    - Bar-Hop for Pride. Heritage of Pride, NYC (Box 33)
    - Hotlanta River Expo (Box 33)
    - AFTERGLOW. The Beauty of Orion (Box 34)
    - Ice palace 57 (Box 34)
    - The Spike New York City (Box 34)
    - Ascension (Box 34)
    - The Saint (Box 34)
    - Logo of the Maya sun calendar (Box 34)
    - GMHC Morning Party 1990 (Box 34)
    - Heritage of Pride Bryant Park NYC June 22, 1997 (Box 34)
    - Rightfully PROUD and fighting on (Box 34)
    - Logo of the occult magic circle table (Box 34)
    - Y Pride Lesbian Gay (Box 34)
    - Strengthen the Ties, Break the Chains. Lesbian/Gay Freedom Day 26 June 1983 San Francisco (Box 34)
    - PRIDE (Box 34)
    - Forward together. No Turning Back Lesbian Gay Freedom Day June 29, 1986 San Francisco (Box 34)
    - Jackhammer San Francisco [boxers] (Box 34)
    - Randoly [?] Elegant (Box 34)
    - The Saint (Box 34)
    - Spirit 10-12-96 (Box 35)
    - Heritage of Pride (Box 35)
    - Climax 1997 (Box 35)
    - Pair of socks (Box 35)
    - Leatherfest V, San Diego (Box 35)
    - Inevitable Love (Box 35)
    - Tricycle 75 (Box 35)
    - Stonewall 25 NYC's 1994 Gay & Lesbian Pride Weekend-Gay Games IV (Box 35)
    - Dance on Washington (Box 35)
    - Art Against AIDS Japan (Box 35)
    - If the Pope had AIDS he'd need more than just your prayers (Box 35)
  - Other [including whistles, patches, frisbee, magnets, pen, fake tattoos, and key chain], 1982-2002, undated (Box 36)
- Audiovisual, 1959-2002; Series V
  The series is arranged in four groups; audiocassettes, VHS videocassettes, photographs, and records. Audiocassettes primarily contain interviews with former members of the Jewel Box Revue. The interviews provide excellent documentation of this transgender and female impersonation show during the 1940s and 1950s, and complement documentation found in Series I. Photographs also include images of the Jewel Box Revue from approximately the same time period. Other photographs document gay pride events and an exhibition of the AIDS quilt. Videocassettes mainly depict events and parades, with some additional home video footage. Instances of poor audio or visual quality have been noted in bracket statements. The records that arrived with the collection are described, but have been transferred to Historical Sound Recordings (HSR) in the Yale University Library. Researchers need to contact HSR to make an appointment to listen to them.
  - Audio materials
    Conditions Governing Access
    Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
    - Baker, Tommy [2 cassettes; originals; restricted], 1984 January 28 (Box 37–38)
    - Cummings, LaVerne [2 cassettes; originals; restricted], 1984 January 28 (Box 39–40)
    - Hale-Loki [original cassette; restricted], 1984 February 9 (Box 41)
    - Jeffrey [promotional songs from the motion picture; original cassette; restricted], 1995 (Box 42)
    - Lazard, Sasha, "Awakening" [2 versions; from the album, The Myth of Red; original compact disk; restricted], 2002 (Box 43)
    - Lee, Harvey [4 cassettes; originals; restricted], 1984 January 25-February 9 (Box 44–47)
    - Marlo, Gino [alone, with Robbie Ross, and with "Barry;" 4 cassettes; originals; restricted ], 1984 January 31, February 1, April 19 (Box 48–51)
    - Marlow, Mickey [original cassette; restricted], 1984 February 12 (Box 52)
    - Massey, Frank [original cassette; restricted], 1982 September 29 (Box 53)
    - Page, Frank [with John DeOlmos; 2 cassettes; original cassettes; restricted], 1984? April 21 (Box 54–55)
    - Price, Robin [also contains interview with Robbie Ross; 2 cassettes; originals; restricted], 1984 February 6, 9 (Box 56–57)
    - Roberts, Dale [with Kirk Wilde; 2 cassettes; originals; restricted], 1982 December 1 (Box 58–59)
    - St. Claire, Al [also contains interview with Robin Price; 3 cassettes; originals; restricted], 1984 January 30, February 6 (Box 60–62)
    - Stoddard, Jud [2 cassettes; originals; restricted], 1984 February 16 (Box 63–64)
    - Tape from answering machine [regarding misuse of Gay Pride Parade committee name by Steve Cohn/Palladium], 1985 (Box 65)
  - Photographs
    - General, 1976-1988, 2001 (Box 66, Folder 1)
    - AIDS quilt, 1988 Jun, undated (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - FAIRPAC event, undated (Box 66, Folder 3)
    - Fire Island, 1985 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Gay Pride parades, 1985-2002 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Jewel Box Revue, undated (Box 66, Folder 6)
    - Kilgallen, Rob, 1959, undated (Box 66, Folder 7)
    - Parties/events, undated (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Videotapes
    - Brooks Jones, M. home movies
      - "Apartment" [includes "AIDS Hits Home," a 1986 CBS special; original videocassette; restricted], undated (Box 67)
      - Working on a paste up [audio consists only of music;original videocassette; restricted ], undated (Box 68)
    - Christopher Street Liberation Day Parade [production of City Heights; original videocassette; restricted], 1983-1984 (Box 69)
    - FAIRPAC roasts
      - Cooperberg, Irving roast [2 videocassettes; poor video; originals; restricted], undated (Box 70–71)
      - Fierstein, Harvey roast [poor audio; original videocassette; restricted], 1987 fall (Box 72)
    - Gay/Lesbian Pride Day March [poor video; original videocassette; restricted], 1987 June 28 (Box 73)
    - Inevitable Love [production of Intelligence in Video, Inc.; original videocassette; restricted], 1986 (Box 74)
    - Mr. Leather New York [poor audio; original videocassette; restricted], 1985 (Box 75)
    - Peoples memorial for Marsha P. Johnson [no audio; original videocassette; restricted], undated (Box 76)
    - San Francisco Gay Freedom Day Parade [production of Design/Fabrication; original videocassette; restricted], 1981-1982 (Box 77)
  - Records
    - "The Deadly Nightshade," untitled album, 1975, an LP record from Phantom Records [To make an appointment to hear this material, contact Historical Sound Recordings where this item is housed.]
    - St. Claire, Al, "Nobody Does It Like Me" and "Am I Blue," n.d., a 45 record from Alabaster Records [To make an appointment to hear this material, contact Historical Sound Recordings where this item is housed.]